<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>翻译测试，英翻中</title>
    <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/137</link>
    <description>原文：

To push the national economy forward is an important instruction of Chairman Mao’s. Building China into a powerful modern socialist country before the end of the century is a grand blueprint personally drawn up by Chairman Mao. However, sharp struggle between the two lines has always existed on the question of the type of modernization and how to realize it. The unrepentant capitalist-roader in the Party never mentioned taking class struggle as the key link but trumpeted the theory of productive forces. He said that he cared only about a rise in the national economy but not how it was to be done. He disapproved of putting proletarian politics in command and peddled “putting profit in command” and “material incentives.” He opposed relying on the masses and advocated the return to “relying on specialists in running factories.” He opposed the policy of building our country independently with the initiative in our own hands and relying on our own efforts, and trumpeted servility to things foreign. If things were done according to his revisionist line, then the nature of socialist ownership would be changed, the relation between men would become one between employers and employees, the capitalist system of distribution would reappear, and socialist relations in production would be undermined. In this way, the result would be that the national economy would fail to develop, or if it developed, it would either be temporary or it would turn out to be modernization of an imperialist or social-imperialist type. Whichever way it might take, production would be hampered and the development of the social productive forces retarded.</description>
    <language>zh-CN</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 08:57:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>闲谈 | 灌水</category>
    <atom:link href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/137.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>翻译测试，英翻中</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[msc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Google翻译<br>
推动国民经济向前发展是毛主席的重要指示。在本世纪末之前将中国建设成一个强大的现代社会主义国家是毛主席亲自制定的宏伟蓝图。但是，在现代化的类型和如何实现这一问题上，两线之间始终存在着激烈的斗争。党内不屈不挠的资本主义行家从来没有提到以阶级斗争为主要纽带，而是吹捧了生产力理论。他说，他只关心国民经济的增长，而不关心这样做的方式。他不赞成将无产阶级政治置于主导地位，并兜售“以暴利为目的”和“实质性诱因”。他反对依靠群众，主张重新回到“依靠专家经营工厂”。他反对以自己的主动和依靠自己的努力自主建立国家的政策，并吹捧对外国事物的奴役。如果按照他的修正主义路线来做，那将改变社会主义所有权的性质，人与人之间的关系将变成雇主与雇员之间的关系，资本主义分配制度将重新出现，社会主义生产关系将受到破坏。这样，结果就是国民经济将无法发展，或者如果发展，它将是暂时的，或者结果将是帝国主义或社会帝国主义类型的现代化。无论采取哪种方式，都会阻碍生产，阻碍社会生产力的发展。</p>
<p>百度翻译<br>
推进国民经济发展是毛主席的重要指示，在本世纪末以前把我国建设成为社会主义现代化强国，是毛主席亲自制定的宏伟蓝图。然而，在现代化的类型和如何实现现代化的问题上，两条路线始终存在着尖锐的斗争。党的资本主义道路坚定不移的人，从来没有提过把阶级斗争作为关键环节，而是大肆宣扬生产力理论。他说他只关心国民经济的增长，而不关心如何实现这一目标。他不赞成无产阶级政治，鼓吹“以利为本”和“物质奖励”；反对依靠群众，主张恢复“依靠专家办厂”；反对独立自主建设国家的方针，反对自己掌握主动权靠自己的努力，大肆宣扬对外国事物的奴性。如果按照他的修正主义路线去做，社会主义所有制的性质就会改变，人与人之间的关系就会变成劳资关系，资本主义的分配制度就会重新出现，社会主义的生产关系就会受到破坏。这样一来，国民经济就发展不起来了，如果发展了，要么是暂时的，要么是帝国主义式的、社会帝国主义式的现代化。无论采取何种方式，都会阻碍生产，阻碍社会生产力的发展。</p>
<p>腾讯翻译</p>
<p>把国民经济推向前进，是毛主席的重要指示，到本世纪末把我国建成社会主义现代化强国，是毛主席亲自擘画的宏伟蓝图。但是，在现代化的类型和如何实现现代化的问题上，两条路线之间始终存在着尖锐的斗争。党内不知悔改的走资派从来没有提到以阶级斗争为纲，而是鼓吹生产力理论。他说，他只关心国民经济的发展，而不关心如何发展。他不赞成无产阶级政治当家作主，兜售“利润当家”和“物质奖励”。他反对依靠群众，主张回归“靠专办厂”。他反对独立自主、自力更生的建国方针，鼓吹对外国的奴才。如果按照他的修正主义路线去做，社会主义所有制的性质就会改变，人与人的关系就会变成劳资关系，资本主义的分配制度就会重新出现，社会主义的生产关系就会受到破坏。这样一来，结果就是国民经济发展不起来，发展起来了，不是暂时的，就是帝国主义的现代化，或者是社会帝国主义的现代化。无论走哪条路，都会阻碍生产，阻碍社会生产力的发展。</p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/137/2">阅读整个主题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/137/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 08:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-137-2</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/137.rss">翻译测试，英翻中</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>翻译测试，英翻中</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[msc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>原文：</p>
<p>To push the national economy forward is an important instruction of Chairman Mao’s. Building China into a powerful modern socialist country before the end of the century is a grand blueprint personally drawn up by Chairman Mao. However, sharp struggle between the two lines has always existed on the question of the type of modernization and how to realize it. The unrepentant capitalist-roader in the Party never mentioned taking class struggle as the key link but trumpeted the theory of productive forces. He said that he cared only about a rise in the national economy but not how it was to be done. He disapproved of putting proletarian politics in command and peddled “putting profit in command” and “material incentives.” He opposed relying on the masses and advocated the return to “relying on specialists in running factories.” He opposed the policy of building our country independently with the initiative in our own hands and relying on our own efforts, and trumpeted servility to things foreign. If things were done according to his revisionist line, then the nature of socialist ownership would be changed, the relation between men would become one between employers and employees, the capitalist system of distribution would reappear, and socialist relations in production would be undermined. In this way, the result would be that the national economy would fail to develop, or if it developed, it would either be temporary or it would turn out to be modernization of an imperialist or social-imperialist type. Whichever way it might take, production would be hampered and the development of the social productive forces retarded.</p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/137/1">阅读整个主题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/137/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 08:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-137-1</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/137.rss">翻译测试，英翻中</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
