<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>语录、术语、宣传用语的英文翻译</title>
    <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/177</link>
    <description>列宁为什么说对资产阶级专政，这个问题要搞清楚。这个问题不搞清楚，就会变修正主义。要使全国知道。

**Why did Lenin speak of exercising dictatorship over the bourgeoisie? This question must be thoroughly understood. “Lack of clarity on this question will lead to revisionism. This should be made known to the whole nation.**</description>
    <language>zh-CN</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 19:04:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>一般讨论</category>
    <atom:link href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/177.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>语录、术语、宣传用语的英文翻译</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[msc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Translation (tentative)</p>
<p><strong>文化大革命是发动广大群众揭发黑暗面的一种方式</strong><br>
The Cultural Revolution is a way to mobilize the masses to expose the dark side</p>
<p><strong>公开地、全面地、由下而上地发动广大群众来揭发我们的黑暗面。</strong><br>
Mobilize the masses to expose our dark side in an open, comprehensive, and bottom-up manner</p>
<p><strong>民主革命后，工人、贫下中农没有停止，他们要革命。而一部分党员却不想前进了，有些人后退了，反对革命了。为什么呢？作了大官了，要保护大官们的利益。</strong></p>
<p>After the democratic revolution, the workers and the poor and lower-middle peasants do not stop, they want the revolution. However, some party members do not want to move forward, while others fall back and oppose the revolution. Why? They have become high-ranking officials, they have to protect the interests of high-ranking officials.</p>
<p><strong>一百年后还要不要革命？一千年后要不要革命？总还是要革命的。总是一部分人觉得受压，小官、学生、工、农、兵，不喜欢大人物压他们，所以他们要革命呢。一万年以后矛盾就看不见了？怎么看不见呢，是看得见的。</strong></p>
<p>Is there still a need for revolution in a hundred years’ time? Is there a need for revolution in a thousand years’ time? There is always a need for revolution. There are always some people who feel oppressed. Junior officials, students, workers, peasants and soldiers do not like big people to oppress them, so they want revolution. Ten thousand years later, the contradiction will be out of sight? Why can’t it be seen? It can be seen.</p>
<p><strong>官僚主义者阶级与工人阶级和贫下中农是两个尖锐对立的阶级</strong></p>
<p>The class of bureaucrats is sharply opposed to the working class and the poor and lower-middle peasants.</p>
<p><strong>管理也是社教。如果管理人员不到车间小组搞三同， 拜老师学一门至几门手艺， 那就一辈子会同工人阶级处于尖锐的阶级斗争状态中， 最后必然要被工人阶级把他们当作资产阶级打倒。不学会技术， 长期当外行，管理也搞不好。以其昏昏， 使人昭昭， 是不行的。</strong></p>
<p>Management is also a socialist education. If managers do not come to the workshop group to practice “three together”, apprentice to learn one to several crafts, they will be in a state of sharp class struggle with the working class all their lives, and in the end they will inevitably be overthrown by the working class as the bourgeoisie. If you do not learn the technology and become a layman for a long time, then the management will not be good. It’s no OK to expect to make others see the light with one’s own darkness and confusion.</p>
<p>note:</p>
<ol>
<li>“three together” : Eat, live, work together</li>
<li>socialist education(movement): <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Socialist_Education_Movement" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Socialist_Education_Movement</a>
</li>
<li>以其昏昏， 使人昭昭:</li>
</ol>
<blockquote>
<p>孟子曰：“贤者以其昭昭，使人昭昭；今以其昏昏，使人昭昭。”</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>昭昭，明也。昏昏，暗也。尹氏曰：“大学之道，在自昭明德，而施于天下国家，其有不顺者寡矣。”</em></p>
<p><strong>这些走资本主义道路的领导人，是已经变成或者正在变成吸工人血的资产阶级分子，他们对社会主义革命的必要性怎么会认识足呢?这些人是斗争对象， 革命对象，社教运动绝对不能依靠他们。我们能依靠的， 只有那些同工人没有仇恨而又有革命精神的干部</strong></p>
<p>These leaders who take the road of capitalism are bourgeois elements who have become or are becoming workers’ blood suckers.How can they be fully aware of the necessity of a socialist revolution?These people are the object of struggle, the object of revolution, and the socialist education movement must not rely on them. We can only rely on those cadres who have no hatred with the workers and have a revolutionary spirit.</p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/177/6">阅读整个主题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/177/6</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 19:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-177-6</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/177.rss">语录、术语、宣传用语的英文翻译</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>语录、术语、宣传用语的英文翻译</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[adt]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><strong>总而言之，中国属于社会主义国家。解放前跟资本主义差不多。现在还实行八级工资制，按劳分配，货币交换，这些跟旧社会没有多少差别。所不同的是所有制变更了。</strong> ”“ <strong>我国现在实行的是商品制度，工资制度也不平等，有八级工资制，等等。这只能在无产阶级专政下加以限制。所以，林彪一类如上台，搞资本主义制度很容易。</strong> ”</p>
<p>“ <strong>In a word, China is a socialist country. Before liberation she was much the same as a capitalist country. Even now she practices an eight-grade wage system, distribution according to work and exchange through money, and in all this differs very little from the old society. What is different is that the system of ownership has been changed.</strong> ” “ <strong>Our country at present practices a commodity system, the wage system is unequal, too, as in the eight-grade wage scale, and so forth. Under the dictatorship of the proletariat such things can only be restricted. Therefore, if people like Lin Piao [Lin Biao] come to power, it will be quite easy for them to rig up the capitalist system.</strong> ”</p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/177/5">阅读整个主题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/177/5</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 12:21:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-177-5</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/177.rss">语录、术语、宣传用语的英文翻译</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>语录、术语、宣传用语的英文翻译</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[adt]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>“据我观察，不讲全体，也不讲绝大多数，恐怕是相当大的一个多数的工厂里头，领导权不在真正的马克思主义者、不在工人群众手里。过去领导工厂的，不是没有好人。有好人，党委书记、副书记、委员，都有好人，支部书记有好人。但是，他是跟着过去刘少奇那种路线走，无非是搞什么物质刺激，利润挂帅，不提倡无产阶级政治，搞什么奖金，等等。”“但是， 工厂里确有坏人”。“就是说明革命没有完”</p>
<p><strong>"Apparently, we couldn’t do without the Great Proletarian Cultural Revolution, for our base was not solid. From m observations, I am afraid that in a fairly large majority of factories — I don’t mean all or the overwhelming majority — leadership was not in the hands of real Marxists and the masses of workers. Not that there were no good people in the leadership of the factories. There were. There were good people among the secretaries, deputy secretaries and members of Party committees and among the Party branch secretaries. But they followed that line of Liu Shao-chi’s, just resorting to material incentive, putting profit in command, and instead of promoting proletarian politics, handing out bonuses, and so forth." “But there are indeed bad people in the factories.” "This shows that the revolution is still unfinished."</strong></p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/177/4">阅读整个主题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/177/4</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 12:19:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-177-4</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/177.rss">语录、术语、宣传用语的英文翻译</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>语录、术语、宣传用语的英文翻译</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[msc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://massline.org/PekingReview/PR1969/PR1969-39-MaoRevUnderDofP.pdf" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://massline.org/PekingReview/PR1969/PR1969-39-MaoRevUnderDofP.pdf</a></p>
<p>Class contradiction, the class struggle between the proletariat and the bourgeoisie and the struggle between the socialist road and the capitalist road exist throughout the transitional period. We shall go astray if we forget this fundamental theory and practice of our Party over the last dozen years or so.</p>
<p>Quoted in “Forward Along the High Road of Mao Tsetung Thought,” Hongqi editorial, No. 13, 1966</p>
<p>社会主义社会是一个相当长的历史阶段。在社会主义这个历史阶段中，还存在着阶级、阶级矛盾和阶级斗争，存在着社会主义同资本主义两条道路的斗争，存在着资本主义复辟的危险性。要认识这种斗争的长期性和复杂性。要提高警惕。要进行社会主义教育。要正确理解和处理阶级矛盾和阶级斗争问题，正确区别和处理敌我矛盾和人民内部矛盾。不然的话，我们这样的社会主义国家，就会走向反面，就会变质，就会出现复辟。我们从现在起，必须年年讲，月月讲，天天讲，使我们对这个问题，有比较清醒的认识，有一条马克思列宁主义的路线</p>
<p>Socialist society covers a considerably long historical period. In the historical period of socialism, there are still classes, class contradictions and class struggle, there is the struggle between the socialist road and the capitalist road, and there is the danger of capitalist restoration. We must recognize the protracted and complex nature of this struggle. We must heighten our vigilance. We must conduct socialist education. We must correctly understand and handle class contradictions and class struggle, distinguish the contradictions between ourselves and the enemy from those among the people and handle them correctly. Otherwise a socialist country like ours will turn into its opposite and degenerate, and capitalist restoration will take place. From now on we must remind ourselves of this every year, every month and every day so that we can retain a rather sober understanding of this problem and have a Marxist-Leninist line.</p>
<p>Quoted in “A Theoretical Weapon for Making Revolution Under the Dictator-ship of the Proletariat - In Commemoration of the 10th Anniversary of the Publication of Chairman Mao’s On the Correct Handling of Contradictirons Among the People,” Hongqi editorial,No. 10. 1967</p>
<p>现在的文化大革命，仅仅是第一次，以后还必然要进行多次。革命的谁胜谁负要在一个很长的历史时期内才能解决。如果弄得不好，资本主义复辟将是随时可能的。全体党员，全国人民，不要以为有二次、三四次文化大革命，就可以太平无事了。千万注意，决不可丧失警惕。<br>
The present great cultural revolution is only the first; there will inevitably be many more in the future. The issue of who will win in the revolution can only be settled over along historical period. If things are not properly handled, it is possible for a capitalist restoration to take place at any time. Let no one in the Party or among the people in our country think that everything will be all right after one or two great cultural revolutions, or three or four. We must be very much on the alert and never lose vigilance.</p>
<p>【待查】</p>
<p>公开地、全面地、由下而上地发动广大群众来揭发我们的黑暗面</p>
<p>民主革命后，工人、贫下中农没有停止，他们要革命。而一部分党员却不想前进了，有些人后退了，反对革命了。为什么呢？作了大官了，要保护大官们的利益。</p>
<p>一百年后还要不要革命？一千年后要不要革命？总还是要革命的。总是一部分人觉得受压，小官、学生、工、农、兵，不喜欢大人物压他们，所以他们要革命呢。一万年以后矛盾就看不见了？怎么看不见呢，是看得见的。</p>
<p>官僚主义者阶级与工人阶级和贫下中农是两个尖锐对立的阶级。</p>
<p>管理也是社教。如果管理人员不到车间小组搞三同， 拜老师学一门至几门手艺， 那就一辈子会同工人阶级处于尖锐的阶级斗争状态中， 最后必然要被工人阶级把他们当作资产阶级打倒。不学会技术， 长期当外行，管理也搞不好。以其昏昏， 使人昭昭， 是不行的。</p>
<p>这些走资本主义道路的领导人，是已经变成或者正在变成吸工人血的资产阶级分子，他们对社会主义革命的必要性怎么会认识足呢?这些人是斗争对象， 革命对象，社教运动绝对不能依靠他们。我们能依靠的， 只有那些同工人没有仇恨而又有革命精神的干部</p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/177/3">阅读整个主题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/177/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 12:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-177-3</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/177.rss">语录、术语、宣传用语的英文翻译</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>语录、术语、宣传用语的英文翻译</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[msc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>什么“三项指示为纲”，安定团结不是不要阶级斗争，阶级斗争是纲，其余都是目。</p>
<p><strong>What ‘taking the three directives as the key link’! Stability and unity do not mean writing off class struggle; class struggle is the key link and everything else hinges on it.</strong></p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/177/2">阅读整个主题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/177/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 12:20:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-177-2</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/177.rss">语录、术语、宣传用语的英文翻译</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>语录、术语、宣传用语的英文翻译</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[msc]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>列宁为什么说对资产阶级专政，这个问题要搞清楚。这个问题不搞清楚，就会变修正主义。要使全国知道。</p>
<p><strong>Why did Lenin speak of exercising dictatorship over the bourgeoisie? This question must be thoroughly understood. “Lack of clarity on this question will lead to revisionism. This should be made known to the whole nation.</strong></p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/177/1">阅读整个主题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/177/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 12:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-177-1</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/177.rss">语录、术语、宣传用语的英文翻译</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
