<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>关于每月评论的小册子A Critique of Soviet Economics</title>
    <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/186</link>
    <description>来自某同志的发言：

《每月评论》的翻译 &lt;读斯大林《苏联社义经济问题》谈话记录&gt;看来是不那么老实的。

无论58年传达件还是后来邓力群的整理件都**没有** 

Stalin&#39;s point of view in his last letter[* Reply to comrades A. V. Sanina and V. G. Venzher. ] is almost altogether wrong. The basic error is mistrust of the peasants. 

这句话。

《谈话》的原文为：

“斯大林最后这封信中关于不把拖拉机卖给农庄的意见，彻底错误。他把国家和集体农民对立起来，不信任农民群众，死死抓住拖拉机不放，理由是说不通的，自己骗了自己”


毛主席多次说过这本书总体是好书：

“ 斯大林写的《苏联社会主义经济问题》，要好好读，要多读几遍。过去看这本书，不感兴趣，现在不同了。为了我们的事业，结合当前的实际问题，学习经济理论著作，比脱离实际专门读书，要好得多，容易懂。目前研究政治经济学问题，有很大的理论意义和现实意义。”

《每月评论》译本则是从全文各处左砍右堆写出一个“ Stalin&#39;s book from first to last says nothing about the superstructure. It is not concerned with people; it considers things, not people. Does the kind of supply system for consumer goods help spur economic development or not? He should have touched on this at the least. Is it better to have commodity production or is it better not to? Everyone has to study this. Stalin&#39;s point of view in his last letter[*] is almost altogether wrong. The basic error is mistrust of the peasants. Parts of the first, second, and third chapters are correct; other parts could have been clearer. For example, the discussion on planned economy is not complete. The rate of development of the Soviet economy is not high enough, although it is faster than the capitalists&#39; rate. Relations between agriculture and industry, as well as between light and heavy industry, are not clearly explained.”

我正式劝同志们做一些翻译工作，免得国际战友上资产阶级学阀的当。

![image|583x500](upload://ecsRbQMMSOHBiXEa48fgtoyBIrS.png)</description>
    <language>zh-CN</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 14:11:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>一般讨论</category>
    <atom:link href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/186.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>关于每月评论的小册子A Critique of Soviet Economics</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[azide]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="attachment" href="/uploads/short-url/knmCsX0sALdISBKm7slX1vIfjyp.pdf">毛泽东读斯大林《苏联社会主义经济问题》谈话记录.pdf</a> (1.4 MB)</p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/186/2">阅读整个主题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/186/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 14:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-186-2</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/186.rss">关于每月评论的小册子A Critique of Soviet Economics</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>关于每月评论的小册子A Critique of Soviet Economics</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[azide]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>来自某同志的发言：</p>
<p>《每月评论》的翻译 &lt;读斯大林《苏联社义经济问题》谈话记录&gt;看来是不那么老实的。</p>
<p>无论58年传达件还是后来邓力群的整理件都<strong>没有</strong></p>
<p>Stalin’s point of view in his last letter[* Reply to comrades A. V. Sanina and V. G. Venzher. ] is almost altogether wrong. The basic error is mistrust of the peasants.</p>
<p>这句话。</p>
<p>《谈话》的原文为：</p>
<p>“斯大林最后这封信中关于不把拖拉机卖给农庄的意见，彻底错误。他把国家和集体农民对立起来，不信任农民群众，死死抓住拖拉机不放，理由是说不通的，自己骗了自己”</p>
<p>毛主席多次说过这本书总体是好书：</p>
<p>“ 斯大林写的《苏联社会主义经济问题》，要好好读，要多读几遍。过去看这本书，不感兴趣，现在不同了。为了我们的事业，结合当前的实际问题，学习经济理论著作，比脱离实际专门读书，要好得多，容易懂。目前研究政治经济学问题，有很大的理论意义和现实意义。”</p>
<p>《每月评论》译本则是从全文各处左砍右堆写出一个“ Stalin’s book from first to last says nothing about the superstructure. It is not concerned with people; it considers things, not people. Does the kind of supply system for consumer goods help spur economic development or not? He should have touched on this at the least. Is it better to have commodity production or is it better not to? Everyone has to study this. Stalin’s point of view in his last letter[*] is almost altogether wrong. The basic error is mistrust of the peasants. Parts of the first, second, and third chapters are correct; other parts could have been clearer. For example, the discussion on planned economy is not complete. The rate of development of the Soviet economy is not high enough, although it is faster than the capitalists’ rate. Relations between agriculture and industry, as well as between light and heavy industry, are not clearly explained.”</p>
<p>我正式劝同志们做一些翻译工作，免得国际战友上资产阶级学阀的当。</p>
<p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://mlmmlm.icu/uploads/default/original/1X/63872a14c5117b8c0d2f20eba1f30f96525e66a8.png" data-download-href="https://mlmmlm.icu/uploads/default/63872a14c5117b8c0d2f20eba1f30f96525e66a8" title="image"><img src="https://mlmmlm.icu/uploads/default/original/1X/63872a14c5117b8c0d2f20eba1f30f96525e66a8.png" alt="image" data-base62-sha1="ecsRbQMMSOHBiXEa48fgtoyBIrS" width="583" height="500" data-small-upload="https://mlmmlm.icu/uploads/default/optimized/1X/63872a14c5117b8c0d2f20eba1f30f96525e66a8_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta"><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">image</span><span class="informations">977×837 40.6 KB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg></div></a></div></p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/186/1">阅读整个主题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/186/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 13:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-186-1</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/186.rss">关于每月评论的小册子A Critique of Soviet Economics</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
