<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>新冠疫情下的中帝社会</title>
    <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699</link>
    <description># 新冠疫情下的中帝社会

出处：《新闻》六月上

&gt;编者按：一名匿名同志将本文交付予我们，委托我们刊载，我们认为此文针砭时弊。非常深刻。且分析得当，很有价值。故刊载。

在2020年的4月，全世界的新冠疫情仍然未能得到有效控制，但中国的疫情已经渐渐稳定下来。于是，最近的一段时间内，所谓“中国成就”、“中国道路”、“中国模式”等等名词又开始甚嚣尘上，可是真的是所谓的“中国体制”让中国率先脱离了疫情的吗？以及，真的是中国当局的“为人民服务”精神让疫情更快结束了吗？的确，此次疫情的克服自然离不开中国政府的指挥，可由此可以得出中国体制存在优越性或者中帝统治阶级真的为人民服务吗？

不，绝不！

想要战胜一次重大的突发公众安全事件，一个国家首先需要什么？是体制吗？显然不是，在有这些体制之前，最起码应当存在充足且可以调动的人力物力。目前作为新兴帝国主义国家的中国，在其广阔的土地中有着丰裕的资源；劳动力人口在世界上数一数二，且大多怀着朴素因而如双刃剑般的爱国情感；拜社会主义时代的建设所赐，其工业产值也名列世界第一，各种各样物资的生产线应有尽有，正是雄厚的物质力量的支撑才能让中国率先走出疫情。反观各老牌帝国主义国家，由于资本贪图快速增殖自身，同时也由于老牌帝国主义国家利润率严重下降，因而资本纷纷流入金融资本当中，这导致了大规模的去工业化，制造业被大量迁往国外，这样下去可以及时动员的物质力量怎么可能充足呢？中国还没有大规模地出现去工业化，很大程度上有赖于中国国内的劳动力还足够廉价，能支撑起资本家的高利润率。

有足够的物质力量可调动，本身只能说明中国是一个新兴的帝国主义国家，相较于老牌帝国主义国家来说还不那么腐朽，绝不能说明别的什么。而且，中国的这种比较好的“抗疫”表现也是建立在官僚资产阶级利用社会主义的名号欺骗大众，并对工人运动施以残酷镇压的基础之上。拿中帝抗疫的“好表现”与老牌帝国主义国家的“坏表现”作对比，实际上等于是拿苏修在切尔诺贝利核事故中的“好表现”与日本在福岛核事故当中的“坏表现”相对比，苏修在切尔诺贝利核事故中的“好表现”并不能掩盖其社会帝国主义的本质，因而同样，中帝在抵抗疫情中的“好表现”同样不能掩盖其帝国主义的本质。

中帝的政治体制是否能在因为中国在此次疫情中的较好表现而被肯定呢？这个答案显然是否定的。从一开始，资产阶级官僚们将疫情中的“吹哨人”以造谣论处；后来随着疫情的持续扩大，才别别扭扭地挤出几个“可防可控”来；到了疫情的攻坚阶段，大搞一刀切，在为居民提供基本的生活物质时，与某些商业资本家沆瀣一气，垄断居民的食物供应，谋取超额利润，有人试图打破垄断却被警方抓了起来，有人试图抗议，接着社区（资产阶级官僚伸往基层的触手）通过以垃圾车运蔬菜的方式对他们进行报复。

更不得不提的是湖北当地的红十字会，侵吞善款和物资，将缺乏物资的公立医院拒之门外，将为领导和莆田系医院准备的物资大把大把地送出。以至于人民群众看不下去了，自发组织起从厂家到医院手中的完整的供应链，绕开红十字会，为公立医院缓解了燃眉之急。人民群众的自发组织“抗疫”行为值得肯定，但这种本值得肯定的行为，却被湖北红十字会及某些政府部门认定为非法，表面说是不利于统一管理，实则不利于统一将贿赂收进资产阶级官僚们的腰包。

可仍然会有人不服气，说什么中国的医疗体系发挥了重要作用，这种公立医疗体系同样是中国体制。的确，社会主义时期留下的公立医疗体系并没有完全消失，公立医院仍然发挥着不小作用。但看问题不能只看当下，更要看趋势。这些年来，随着中帝当局的“深化改革”或者说新自由主义式倒退，一切都在朝着私有化大步迈进，医疗行业也不例外。这些年来害死魏泽西的那种“莆田系”医疗（实际上就是私营医疗的一种）正如“雨后春笋”般“拔地而起”，与此同时公立医院遭到了剧烈的挤压，其一方面勉力承载着人民的信任，另一方面经费却年年削减，人才也年年流失，很多本属公立医院的医生为了谋生被迫去了私营医院。而此次疫情中私营医院几乎没有发挥任何积极作用。另外，医疗等的社会保障并不是所谓“社会主义的中国”才有的，英国就有国民医疗服务体系（NHS），但没人认为英国是一个社会主义国家。认为中国的公立医疗体系发挥了重要作用，因而认为中国是社会主义国家的人显然根本不懂什么是社会主义。

显然，疫情的较早缓解根本不能证明中帝的政治体制具有优越性，用疫情较早缓解来说明中帝在根本上高于其他老牌帝国主义国家显然非常不正确。

那么，中帝当局对疫情的积极应对真的是出于为人民服务的思想吗？

中国此次抗击疫情的相对有力，是因为占尽了世界工厂地位的便宜，这本质上是对工人的无情压榨之上的有力。而中帝当局控制疫情的目的，不是什么“救民于水火”，而纯粹就是维护资本主义的生产秩序，毕竟，要是工人、劳动者全都病倒了，资产阶级还怎么剥得剩余价值？

而且，在此前疫情还没有缓解时，中帝资产阶级就迫不及待地加大剥削与压迫的力度了。为抗击疫情作出巨大贡献的雷神山、火神山医院的建设工人，被拖欠工资不算，还要以隔离伙食费的名义进一步压榨，同时被拖欠的工资甚至也遭巧立名目克扣缩减到了原有水平的1%，有部分工人进行了抗议，但换来的不是别的，是镇压，是警棍、讯问与拘留；医疗器材厂工人的奖金以及其他收入，也被老板以抗击疫情的名义取消了；在抗疫一线奋战的女性医生女护士被中帝当局用作宣传工具，一些女护士流着泪地被迫剃掉头发，一些派往重灾区的女医护被迫放弃应得的补助，来表现所谓巨大牺牲；大量医护一方面用最大的努力抗击着疫情，另一方面却只能拿到基本工资，甚至连基本工资也拿不全。

疫情于普通民众而言也是一次隐私权和隐私大规模丢失的时光。特色政府打着管控疫情的旗号，强迫居民安装带有大量漏洞和后门的政府软件，并要求居民再三上报个人信息，还强行让居民使用可以清楚地了解到居民的动向的“健康码”，实际上就是监控码，监控码可以在被扫描的瞬间让政府了解到你的具体动向，即你都去过什么地方，再加上政府软件本身就内置了很多用于监控的后门，居民的一言一行及使用软件的情况可能都会遭到记录。更可怕的是以监控码为代表的数字霸权很有可能会因为政府认定疫情长期存在而一直延续到疫情事实上结束以后。实际上正如中国一些民主主义者说的那样，“防民胜于防病毒”。

而现在，在疫情刚有缓解但还没有彻底消退的时刻，复工复产，或者说恢复资本主义生产秩序已经被中帝当局提上日程了。在推动复工复产的时候，中帝当局对于老板无比慷慨，给予了大量补助和低息贷款，却不对处境危急的劳动者们提供必须的补助，至多是打发乞丐般发点微不足道的钱了事。一个名叫“工号51”的中国马克思主义工人小组记录了一些事实：当局的人社部非常放肆地宣称“企业可以协商降低员工工资、拖欠工资”，“停产期间，工人所得到的假期将把所有年假占用”，同时在工作时感染新冠肺炎将不计入工伤因而不能得到赔偿；富士康一个吸收了大量廉价劳动力的巨型制造业集团———在各地工厂裁去了不可计量的临时工；一个名叫海信的国际化企业集团被曝裁员上万人；在深圳，一个普通的外卖人员无故遭到城管（类似于街头警察）的殴打，警察暴力正在泛滥；比亚迪公司这一汽车制造业巨头给部分员工每个月300元人民币的工资，这在中国的一二线城市内至多只够3天的饭钱；最后，根据民间进步人士分析，中国的失业率已近20%。

工号51小组的记录与进步人士的分析证明，劳动人民正在遭受着前所未有的痛苦，劳动人民正在遭受着剧烈的压迫，但是当局仍在隐瞒人民所遭受的困难，用镇压与虚假宣传营造着不存在的歌舞升平。以上事实完全可以证明，中帝当局这个垄断资产阶级的专制巨人根本不是为人民服务，而是为资产阶级的利益服务。

而对于那些已经康复的新冠肺炎患者呢？对于他们就是迎接新生了吗？并不是，新冠肺炎的治愈只是他们苦难的开始。癌症患者因为曾得过新冠肺炎，被医院区别对待，以至于延误了治疗，癌细胞大大扩散，病情严重加剧；那些康复后相对健康的患者，仍然受到歧视，以至于再就业成了比登天还难的事情，只能坐吃山空；而一些生活还过得去的患者由于没有被积极地进行心理疏导患上了创伤后应激障碍（PTSD），每日生活在失眠与焦虑之中。康复者仍然生活在阴影下，他们中的不少人出现了自杀倾向。他们虽然战胜了肺炎，却无法战胜水深火热的生活和人吃人的社会，这时候“全心全意为人民服务”的党呢？说是为居民服务的社区呢？

但是，必须指出的是中国人民首先在此次疫情中付出的巨大牺牲。由于病毒肆虐正值中国的传统节日春节，原本休假的医疗器材厂工人、部分建设火神山雷神山等临时医院的工人、医生以及快递外卖配送员等不可计数的劳动者们义无反顾地放弃与家人的团聚，放弃了自己的休假，冒着被感染的风险，回到了自己的岗位上。而不需要紧急复工的其他群众也听从了安排，顶着失业与降薪的压力呆在家里整整两个月。正是中国人民所付出的巨大牺牲，使得疫情最终得到了控制。这是中国人民的朴素的爱国情怀所带来的组织性，说明中国人民完全可以很好地组织起来。中国人民为控制疫情做出的牺牲值得肯定，中国人民在疫情中表现出的组织性证明着其拥有的巨大革命潜力。

当中国人民的朴素爱国情怀转化成无产阶级的革命精神时，资本主义的末日就将来临，中国的革命者将在马列毛主义指导下各员一层共同奋励，不断深入到群众中去，让广大群众为了革命而组织起来，最终将反动派溺死在人民战争的汪洋大海中。</description>
    <language>zh-CN</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 21:44:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>文献 | 书籍</category>
    <atom:link href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>新冠疫情下的中帝社会</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[socialist_appeal]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>这篇文章在去年这个时候的情况看，作为一篇时事分析是极好的。现在看来有点稍显简陋，尤其是论述复工复产的时候，对资本主义性质分析太弱，没有引入再生产概念，这样的文章在内部的效果极好，可是拿去宣传说服力就不太多了。</p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699/8">阅读整个主题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699/8</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 21:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-699-8</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699.rss">新冠疫情下的中帝社会</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>新冠疫情下的中帝社会</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[news_porter]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>好的，感谢各位。</p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699/7">阅读整个主题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699/7</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 02:22:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-699-7</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699.rss">新冠疫情下的中帝社会</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>新冠疫情下的中帝社会</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[None]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>这两者之间从已有信息上看并不存在什么联系，不应该匆忙下定论。具体的其他人已经说得很好了。标题和内容已经重新做了修改。</p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699/6">阅读整个主题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699/6</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 16:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-699-6</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699.rss">新冠疫情下的中帝社会</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>新冠疫情下的中帝社会</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[sdgjdfgh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>这篇文章完全不能确定实际作者，当然，最好在最终胜利到来前永远也确认不了。</p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699/5">阅读整个主题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699/5</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 15:51:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-699-5</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699.rss">新冠疫情下的中帝社会</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>新冠疫情下的中帝社会</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ILA-80]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>不知道你们是怎么确认的。原文写的是“一个地下马列毛主义小组”，而不是共产主义小组（毛主义）的名字。其次，这篇文章有很大部分与共产主义小组（毛主义）签署的文件中有着不同的立场。举例来说，关于“新兴的帝国主义国家”的性质以及“朴素爱国情怀”的作用。</p>
<p>最后，我要提醒同志们在没有得到确定的消息的情况下时最好不要把可能是两个不同的组织联系起来。一是安全上的考虑，二是路线问题。我们都希望毛主义的团结，团结是建立在斗争的基础上的。目前来看，中国存在着一些地上或是半地下的进步大小团体和个人，其中一些号称“马列毛主义”，但是其中存在着许多对这个概念的不同认识。这一点有必要得到考虑。</p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699/4">阅读整个主题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699/4</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 15:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-699-4</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699.rss">新冠疫情下的中帝社会</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>新冠疫情下的中帝社会</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[news_porter]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <h1>China under the COVID-19 Epidemic</h1>
<p><em>We received the following article from an underground MLM group based in China.</em></p>
<p>In April 2020, although the epidemic in most countries has still not been effectively controlled, the epidemic in China has gradually stabilized. So in the recent period of time, the so-called “China achievements”, “China road”, “China model” and other terms began to clamor by the drummer of Chinese imperialism, but is it really the so-called “Chinese system” that let China take the lead out of the epidemic? And, is it really the spirit of “serving the people” of the Chinese authorities that ended the epidemic more quickly? Indeed, the overcoming of the epidemic cannot be achieved without the command of the Chinese authorities,but can it be concluded from this that the Chinese system has advantages or that the ruling class of the imperialist China really serves the people?</p>
<p>No, never!</p>
<p>To overcome a major public safety emergency, what does a country need first? Is it a political system? Obviously not, before these systems, at least there should be sufficient and mobilizable manpower and material resources. At present, China, as an emerging imperialist country, has abundant resources in its vast land; imperialist China has the most and best laborers in the world , and most of them have the simplicity patriotic sentiment and thus like a double-edged swords(Make them fooled by the bourgeoisie); thanks to the construction of the socialist era, imperialist China’s industrial output value also ranks first in the world, and there are all kinds of production lines for various materials. It is the support of strong material forces that will allow China to take the lead in getting out of the epidemic. In contrast, in the old imperialist countries like America etc, due to the capital ’s greed to rapidly multiply themselves, and because the rate of surplus value of the old imperialist countries has seriously declined, capital has flowed into financial capital, which has led to large-scale deindustrialization, and manufacturing has been relocated abroad, How can the material power that can be mobilized in time be sufficient under these circumstances? China has not yet undergone large-scale deindustrialization, largely because China’s domestic labor is still cheap enough to support the capitalists’ high surplus value rate.</p>
<p>There is enough material power to mobilize can only show that China is an emerging imperialist country,so compared with the old imperialist countries, it is not so decaying, and it can never explain anything else. Moreover, China’s better “anti-epidemic” performance is also based on the state monopoly bourgeoisie using the name of socialism to deceive the public and using the truncheons to brutally suppress the workers’ movement. Comparing the “good performance” of the anti-epidemic disease of China with the “bad performance” of the old imperialist countries is actually the same as comparing the “good performance” of the revisionist Soviet Union in the Chernobyl nuclear accident with the “bad performance” of Japan in the Fukushima nuclear accident.Revisionist USSR’s “good performance” in the Chernobyl nuclear accident could not conceal the essence of his social imperialism. Similarly, the essence of china imperialism cannot be covered up by the “good performance” in anti-epidemic.</p>
<p>Can China’s political system be affirmed by China’s better performance in this epidemic? The answer is obviously no. From the beginning, the bourgeois bureaucrats punished the “whistler” of the epidemic as a rumor.;later, as the epidemic continued to expand, they was only squeezing out a few words like “preventable and controllable”; time to tackle the epidemic, they colluded with some commercial capitalists like sewage and stench to monopolize the food supply to obtain excess profits when providing basic living materials to residents.Some people try to break the monopoly but they are caught by the police, some people try to protest, and then the community (The tentacles of the bourgeois bureaucracy reaching the grassroots level) retaliated against them by transporting vegetables in garbage trucks.</p>
<p>What has to be mentioned is that the local Red Cross in Hubei embezzled funds and materials, rejected public hospitals that lacked materials, and sent a lot of materials for the leaders and private hospital. This phenomenon is so open and shameless that the masses of the people can’t stand it any longer. People spontaneously organize the complete supply chain from manufacturers to hospitals, bypassing the Red Cross, and alleviating the urgent need from public hospitals. The spontaneous organization of the “anti-epidemic” behavior by the people is worthy of recognition, but this worthy behavior is recognized as illegal by the Hubei Red Cross and certain government departments.On the surface, it is not favorable to unified management, but actually，it is not favorable to taken bribe into the pockets of the bourgeois bureaucrats.</p>
<p>But there will still be people who are not convinced,and said China’s medical system has played an important role,this public medical system is also a China-specific system.Indeed, the public medical system left over during the socialist period has not completely disappeared, and public hospitals still play an important role. But looking at the problem should not only look at the present, but also the trend. Over the years, with the “deepening reform” or neo-liberalism retrogression of the Chinese imperialist authorities, everything is moving towards privatization, and the medical industry is no exception. The kind of “Putian” hospital (actually a kind of private hospital) that killed Wei Zexi has “raised up” like a “Spring rushroom”over the years . At the same time, public hospitals have been squeezed violently. Trying to bear the trust of the people, on the other hand, the funds have been cut year by year, and talents have been lost year by year. Many doctors in public hospitals are forced to go to private hospitals to make a living. But in this epidemic, private hospitals hardly played any positive role. In addition, social security such as medical treatment is not unique to the so-called “socialist China”. Britain has a National Service System (NHS), but no one thinks that Britain is a socialist country. People who think that China’s public medical system has played an important role, and therefore think that China is a socialist country obviously do not understand what socialism is.</p>
<p>Obviously, the earlier relief of the epidemic simply cannot prove the superiority of the Chinese imperialist political system. Using the earlier relief of the epidemic to show that the imperialist Chinese is fundamentally higher than other old imperialist countries is obviously very incorrect.</p>
<p>Then, is the positive response of the imperialist Chinese authorities to the epidemic really out of the idea of serving the people?</p>
<p>China’s relative advantage in combating epidemics is that it has an advantage as a global factory, which is essentially powerful on the relentless squeeze on workers. The purpose of the imperialist Chinese’s authorities to control the epidemic was not to “save the people against disaster “, but to maintain the capitalist production order. After all, if the workers were all ill, how would the bourgeoisie exploit the surplus value?</p>
<p>Moreover, before the epidemic had been alleviated, the Chinese imperialist bourgeoisie could not wait to increase the intensity of exploitation and oppression. The construction workers of Leishenshan hospital and Huoshenshan Hospitals, which have made great contributions to the fight against the epidemic, are not only being owed wages, but also be further squeezed in the name of food expenses in isolation, at the same time, the wages that have been owed have even been reduced to 1% of the original level by clever deductions, some workers protested, but what was exchanged was nothing other than suppression, batons, interrogation, and detention; bonuses and other incomes for medical equipment factory workers were also canceled by the boss in the name of fighting the epidemic; the female doctors and nurses who worked hard to fight the epidemic were used as propaganda tools by the Chinese authorities to show a huge sacrifice, some female nurses were forced to shave their hair in tears, some female medical staff sent to the critical epidemic area are forced to give up the subsidies they deserve; on the one hand, a large amount of medical personnel uses the greatest efforts to fight the epidemic, but on the other hand, they can only get basic wages, even the basic wages are not complete.</p>
<p>Now, at the moment when the epidemic has just eased but has not completely subsided, the resumption of work and production, or the restoration of the capitalist production order, has been put on the agenda by the imperialist Chinese authorities. When promoting the resumption of work production, the imperialist Chinese authorities were extremely generous to the bourgeoisie, giving a lot of subsidies and low-interest loans or even interest-free loans, but did not provide the necessary subsidies to the workers in crisis. At the most, it was a beggar-like payment of negligible money . A Chinese Marxist worker group recorded some facts: the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security(MOHRSS) of the authorities very brazenly declared that “enterprise can negotiate to reduce employee wages and arrears of wages”, “When production is suspended, the worker’s vacation will take up all annual leave”, and at the same time Infected with COVID-19 during work will not be counted as work injury and therefore cannot be compensated; Foxconn-a giant manufacturing group that has absorbed a lot of cheap labor-has cut out unquantifiable temporary workers in factories everywhere; an international enterprise group named Hisense was exposed to layoffs of tens of thousands of people; in Shenzhen, an ordinary takeaway worker was beaten by Chengguan (Urban Administrative and Law Enforcement Bureau Officers) for no reason, police violence is rampant; BYD, an automobile manufacturing giant, given the salary of 300 yuan per month to many employees, which is only enough for three days of food in China’s first or second tier cities. Finally, according to the analysis of a private progressivesintellectual, China’s unemployment rate is nearly 20%.</p>
<p>The records of the Marxism worker group and the analysis of the progressives intellectual prove that the working people are suffering unprecedented pain, the working people are suffering violent oppression, but the authorities are still concealing the difficulties suffered by the people, using repression and fake propaganda to create a harmonious scene that does not exist . The above facts can fully prove that the tyrannical giant of the monopoly bourgeoisie of the Chinese imperial authorities did not serve the people at all, but served the interests of the bourgeoisie.</p>
<p>In addition, it must be pointed out that the Chinese people first made a huge sacrifice in this epidemic. Because the virus is raging during the traditional Chinese Spring Festival, the medical equipment factory workers who were on vacation, some workers who built Huoshenshan hospital and Leishenshan hospital, doctors and courier delivery personnel and other uncountable laborers have given up to their family members Reunited, gave up their vacation, faced the risk of infection, and returned to his work. Other people who don’t need to resume work urgently follow the arrangement and stay at home for two months under the pressure of unemployment and salary cuts. It was the huge sacrifices made by the Chinese people that brought the epidemic situation under control. This is the organization brought by the simplicity patriotic sentiment of the Chinese people, which shows that the Chinese people can organize well. The sacrifices made by the Chinese people to control the epidemic are worthy of recognition, The organization shown by the Chinese people in the epidemic proves the huge revolutionary potential they possess.</p>
<p>When the simplicity patriotic sentiment of the Chinese people are transformed into the revolutionary spirit of the proletariat, the end of the imperialist Chinese will come, the Chinese people with a glorious revolutionary tradition will stand up again and completely defeat the autocratic tyranny of the monopoly bourgeoisie! The Chinese revolutionaries will work together and joins the effort under the guidance of Marxism-Leninism-Maoism, and will reach the masses continuously. Let the masses organize for the revolution and eventually drown the reactionaries in the vast ocean of the people’s war!</p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699/3">阅读整个主题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699/3</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 13:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-699-3</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699.rss">新冠疫情下的中帝社会</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>新冠疫情下的中帝社会</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[news_porter]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Redspark出处：<br>
<a href="https://www.redspark.nu/en/imperialist-states/china-under-the-covid-19-epidemic/" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://www.redspark.nu/en/imperialist-states/china-under-the-covid-19-epidemic/</a></p>
<p>NewEpoch出处：<br>
<a href="https://www.newepoch.media/post/2020/05/28/china-under-the-covid-19-epidemic" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://www.newepoch.media/post/2020/05/28/china-under-the-covid-19-epidemic</a></p>
<p>Demvolkedienen出处：<br>
<a href="https://www.demvolkedienen.org/index.php/en/48-nachrichten/asi/3981-news-from-china" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://www.demvolkedienen.org/index.php/en/48-nachrichten/asi/3981-news-from-china</a></p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699/2">阅读整个主题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 13:06:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-699-2</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699.rss">新冠疫情下的中帝社会</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>新冠疫情下的中帝社会</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[news_porter]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <h1>新冠疫情下的中帝社会</h1>
<p>出处：《新闻》六月上</p>
<blockquote>
<p>编者按：一名匿名同志将本文交付予我们，委托我们刊载，我们认为此文针砭时弊。非常深刻。且分析得当，很有价值。故刊载。</p>
</blockquote>
<p>在2020年的4月，全世界的新冠疫情仍然未能得到有效控制，但中国的疫情已经渐渐稳定下来。于是，最近的一段时间内，所谓“中国成就”、“中国道路”、“中国模式”等等名词又开始甚嚣尘上，可是真的是所谓的“中国体制”让中国率先脱离了疫情的吗？以及，真的是中国当局的“为人民服务”精神让疫情更快结束了吗？的确，此次疫情的克服自然离不开中国政府的指挥，可由此可以得出中国体制存在优越性或者中帝统治阶级真的为人民服务吗？</p>
<p>不，绝不！</p>
<p>想要战胜一次重大的突发公众安全事件，一个国家首先需要什么？是体制吗？显然不是，在有这些体制之前，最起码应当存在充足且可以调动的人力物力。目前作为新兴帝国主义国家的中国，在其广阔的土地中有着丰裕的资源；劳动力人口在世界上数一数二，且大多怀着朴素因而如双刃剑般的爱国情感；拜社会主义时代的建设所赐，其工业产值也名列世界第一，各种各样物资的生产线应有尽有，正是雄厚的物质力量的支撑才能让中国率先走出疫情。反观各老牌帝国主义国家，由于资本贪图快速增殖自身，同时也由于老牌帝国主义国家利润率严重下降，因而资本纷纷流入金融资本当中，这导致了大规模的去工业化，制造业被大量迁往国外，这样下去可以及时动员的物质力量怎么可能充足呢？中国还没有大规模地出现去工业化，很大程度上有赖于中国国内的劳动力还足够廉价，能支撑起资本家的高利润率。</p>
<p>有足够的物质力量可调动，本身只能说明中国是一个新兴的帝国主义国家，相较于老牌帝国主义国家来说还不那么腐朽，绝不能说明别的什么。而且，中国的这种比较好的“抗疫”表现也是建立在官僚资产阶级利用社会主义的名号欺骗大众，并对工人运动施以残酷镇压的基础之上。拿中帝抗疫的“好表现”与老牌帝国主义国家的“坏表现”作对比，实际上等于是拿苏修在切尔诺贝利核事故中的“好表现”与日本在福岛核事故当中的“坏表现”相对比，苏修在切尔诺贝利核事故中的“好表现”并不能掩盖其社会帝国主义的本质，因而同样，中帝在抵抗疫情中的“好表现”同样不能掩盖其帝国主义的本质。</p>
<p>中帝的政治体制是否能在因为中国在此次疫情中的较好表现而被肯定呢？这个答案显然是否定的。从一开始，资产阶级官僚们将疫情中的“吹哨人”以造谣论处；后来随着疫情的持续扩大，才别别扭扭地挤出几个“可防可控”来；到了疫情的攻坚阶段，大搞一刀切，在为居民提供基本的生活物质时，与某些商业资本家沆瀣一气，垄断居民的食物供应，谋取超额利润，有人试图打破垄断却被警方抓了起来，有人试图抗议，接着社区（资产阶级官僚伸往基层的触手）通过以垃圾车运蔬菜的方式对他们进行报复。</p>
<p>更不得不提的是湖北当地的红十字会，侵吞善款和物资，将缺乏物资的公立医院拒之门外，将为领导和莆田系医院准备的物资大把大把地送出。以至于人民群众看不下去了，自发组织起从厂家到医院手中的完整的供应链，绕开红十字会，为公立医院缓解了燃眉之急。人民群众的自发组织“抗疫”行为值得肯定，但这种本值得肯定的行为，却被湖北红十字会及某些政府部门认定为非法，表面说是不利于统一管理，实则不利于统一将贿赂收进资产阶级官僚们的腰包。</p>
<p>可仍然会有人不服气，说什么中国的医疗体系发挥了重要作用，这种公立医疗体系同样是中国体制。的确，社会主义时期留下的公立医疗体系并没有完全消失，公立医院仍然发挥着不小作用。但看问题不能只看当下，更要看趋势。这些年来，随着中帝当局的“深化改革”或者说新自由主义式倒退，一切都在朝着私有化大步迈进，医疗行业也不例外。这些年来害死魏泽西的那种“莆田系”医疗（实际上就是私营医疗的一种）正如“雨后春笋”般“拔地而起”，与此同时公立医院遭到了剧烈的挤压，其一方面勉力承载着人民的信任，另一方面经费却年年削减，人才也年年流失，很多本属公立医院的医生为了谋生被迫去了私营医院。而此次疫情中私营医院几乎没有发挥任何积极作用。另外，医疗等的社会保障并不是所谓“社会主义的中国”才有的，英国就有国民医疗服务体系（NHS），但没人认为英国是一个社会主义国家。认为中国的公立医疗体系发挥了重要作用，因而认为中国是社会主义国家的人显然根本不懂什么是社会主义。</p>
<p>显然，疫情的较早缓解根本不能证明中帝的政治体制具有优越性，用疫情较早缓解来说明中帝在根本上高于其他老牌帝国主义国家显然非常不正确。</p>
<p>那么，中帝当局对疫情的积极应对真的是出于为人民服务的思想吗？</p>
<p>中国此次抗击疫情的相对有力，是因为占尽了世界工厂地位的便宜，这本质上是对工人的无情压榨之上的有力。而中帝当局控制疫情的目的，不是什么“救民于水火”，而纯粹就是维护资本主义的生产秩序，毕竟，要是工人、劳动者全都病倒了，资产阶级还怎么剥得剩余价值？</p>
<p>而且，在此前疫情还没有缓解时，中帝资产阶级就迫不及待地加大剥削与压迫的力度了。为抗击疫情作出巨大贡献的雷神山、火神山医院的建设工人，被拖欠工资不算，还要以隔离伙食费的名义进一步压榨，同时被拖欠的工资甚至也遭巧立名目克扣缩减到了原有水平的1%，有部分工人进行了抗议，但换来的不是别的，是镇压，是警棍、讯问与拘留；医疗器材厂工人的奖金以及其他收入，也被老板以抗击疫情的名义取消了；在抗疫一线奋战的女性医生女护士被中帝当局用作宣传工具，一些女护士流着泪地被迫剃掉头发，一些派往重灾区的女医护被迫放弃应得的补助，来表现所谓巨大牺牲；大量医护一方面用最大的努力抗击着疫情，另一方面却只能拿到基本工资，甚至连基本工资也拿不全。</p>
<p>疫情于普通民众而言也是一次隐私权和隐私大规模丢失的时光。特色政府打着管控疫情的旗号，强迫居民安装带有大量漏洞和后门的政府软件，并要求居民再三上报个人信息，还强行让居民使用可以清楚地了解到居民的动向的“健康码”，实际上就是监控码，监控码可以在被扫描的瞬间让政府了解到你的具体动向，即你都去过什么地方，再加上政府软件本身就内置了很多用于监控的后门，居民的一言一行及使用软件的情况可能都会遭到记录。更可怕的是以监控码为代表的数字霸权很有可能会因为政府认定疫情长期存在而一直延续到疫情事实上结束以后。实际上正如中国一些民主主义者说的那样，“防民胜于防病毒”。</p>
<p>而现在，在疫情刚有缓解但还没有彻底消退的时刻，复工复产，或者说恢复资本主义生产秩序已经被中帝当局提上日程了。在推动复工复产的时候，中帝当局对于老板无比慷慨，给予了大量补助和低息贷款，却不对处境危急的劳动者们提供必须的补助，至多是打发乞丐般发点微不足道的钱了事。一个名叫“工号51”的中国马克思主义工人小组记录了一些事实：当局的人社部非常放肆地宣称“企业可以协商降低员工工资、拖欠工资”，“停产期间，工人所得到的假期将把所有年假占用”，同时在工作时感染新冠肺炎将不计入工伤因而不能得到赔偿；富士康一个吸收了大量廉价劳动力的巨型制造业集团———在各地工厂裁去了不可计量的临时工；一个名叫海信的国际化企业集团被曝裁员上万人；在深圳，一个普通的外卖人员无故遭到城管（类似于街头警察）的殴打，警察暴力正在泛滥；比亚迪公司这一汽车制造业巨头给部分员工每个月300元人民币的工资，这在中国的一二线城市内至多只够3天的饭钱；最后，根据民间进步人士分析，中国的失业率已近20%。</p>
<p>工号51小组的记录与进步人士的分析证明，劳动人民正在遭受着前所未有的痛苦，劳动人民正在遭受着剧烈的压迫，但是当局仍在隐瞒人民所遭受的困难，用镇压与虚假宣传营造着不存在的歌舞升平。以上事实完全可以证明，中帝当局这个垄断资产阶级的专制巨人根本不是为人民服务，而是为资产阶级的利益服务。</p>
<p>而对于那些已经康复的新冠肺炎患者呢？对于他们就是迎接新生了吗？并不是，新冠肺炎的治愈只是他们苦难的开始。癌症患者因为曾得过新冠肺炎，被医院区别对待，以至于延误了治疗，癌细胞大大扩散，病情严重加剧；那些康复后相对健康的患者，仍然受到歧视，以至于再就业成了比登天还难的事情，只能坐吃山空；而一些生活还过得去的患者由于没有被积极地进行心理疏导患上了创伤后应激障碍（PTSD），每日生活在失眠与焦虑之中。康复者仍然生活在阴影下，他们中的不少人出现了自杀倾向。他们虽然战胜了肺炎，却无法战胜水深火热的生活和人吃人的社会，这时候“全心全意为人民服务”的党呢？说是为居民服务的社区呢？</p>
<p>但是，必须指出的是中国人民首先在此次疫情中付出的巨大牺牲。由于病毒肆虐正值中国的传统节日春节，原本休假的医疗器材厂工人、部分建设火神山雷神山等临时医院的工人、医生以及快递外卖配送员等不可计数的劳动者们义无反顾地放弃与家人的团聚，放弃了自己的休假，冒着被感染的风险，回到了自己的岗位上。而不需要紧急复工的其他群众也听从了安排，顶着失业与降薪的压力呆在家里整整两个月。正是中国人民所付出的巨大牺牲，使得疫情最终得到了控制。这是中国人民的朴素的爱国情怀所带来的组织性，说明中国人民完全可以很好地组织起来。中国人民为控制疫情做出的牺牲值得肯定，中国人民在疫情中表现出的组织性证明着其拥有的巨大革命潜力。</p>
<p>当中国人民的朴素爱国情怀转化成无产阶级的革命精神时，资本主义的末日就将来临，中国的革命者将在马列毛主义指导下各员一层共同奋励，不断深入到群众中去，让广大群众为了革命而组织起来，最终将反动派溺死在人民战争的汪洋大海中。</p>
          <p><a href="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699/1">阅读整个主题</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 09:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">mlmmlm.icu-post-699-1</guid>
        <source url="https://mlmmlm.icu/t/topic/699.rss">新冠疫情下的中帝社会</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
